Guide to the Russell Hoban Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1956-2011; Series I; 36.83; (79 boxes)
  - Novels
    - Unsorted notes and drafts, undated (Box 36)
    - Unsorted notes and drafts, undated (Box 36)
    - Unsorted notes and drafts, undated (Box 36)
    - Unsorted notes and drafts, undated (Box 37)
    - Unsorted notes and drafts, undated (Box 37)
    - Unsorted notes and drafts, undated (Box 37)
    - Unsorted notes and drafts, undated (Box 37)
    - Pilgermann--draft (1st half), 1980-1981 (Box 38)
    - Pilgermann--draft (2nd half), 1981 (Box 38)
    - Pilgermann--final text (1st half), 1981 (Box 38)
    - Pilgermann--final text (2nd half), 1981-1982 (Box 38)
    - Pilgermann--notes (photocopied), 1980 (Box 39)
    - Pilgermann--working notes, 1980 (Box 39)
    - Pilgermann--working notes, 1980 (Box 39)
    - Pilgermann--working notes, 1980 (Box 39)
    - Pilgermann--notes, 1981 (Box 39)
    - Israel diary (1st half), 1980-1981 (Box 39)
    - Israel diary (2nd half) and Pilgermann notes, circa 1980-1981 (Box 39)
    - Bible notes for Pilgermann, circa 1980-1981 (Box 39)
    - Pilgermann--notes (1st half), 1980-1981 (Box 39)
    - Pilgermann--notes (2nd half), circa 1980-1981 (Box 40)
    - Pilgermann--disordered and random notes, 1980-1982 (Box 40)
    - Medusa Frequency--early drafts, 1982 (Box 41)
    - Medusa Frequency--early drafts, 1982 (Box 41)
    - Medusa Frequency--early draft, 1982 (Box 41)
    - Medusa Frequency--early draft, 1982 (Box 41)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (pages 1-113), 1982 (Box 41)
    - Collection entitled "Medusa Frequency--Various Pages", 1982 (Box 41)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
    - Medusa Frequency--early draft and notes, 1982-1983 (Box 41)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1983 (Box 41)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1983 (Box 42)
    - Medusa Frequency--drafts, 1982-1983 (Box 42)
    - Medusa Frequency--early draft, circa 1983 (Box 42)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (pages 1-182), 1983 (Box 42)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1983 (Box 42)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes, circa 1983 (Box 42)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (pages 1-103), 1983 (Box 42)
    - Medusa Frequency--drafts (odd pages), 1983 (Box 42)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1983 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--many unordered drafts, 1983 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes, 1983-1984 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes, 1984 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1984 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--early draft, 1984 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--drafts and pages, 1984-1986 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes, 1985 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes, circa 1985 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (Chapter 1-4), 1985 (Box 43)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1984-1985 (Box 44)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1985 (Box 44)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (pages 1-43), 1986 (Box 44)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (Chapter 1-3), 1986 (Box 44)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (Chapter 1-11), 1986 (Box 44)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (Chapter 1-11), circa 1986 (Box 44)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes, 1986 (Box 44)
    - Medusa Frequency--drafts (random chapters), 1986 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--handwritten notes, 1986 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (Chapter 1-13), 1986 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (Chapter 1-8), 1986 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes, 1986 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--handwritten notes, circa 1986 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes, 1986 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes and list of amendments, 1986 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1986-1987 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft, 1986 (Box 45)
    - Medusa Frequency--draft (chapters and notes), 1988 (Box 46)
    - Medusa Frequency--drafts (variants), 1987-1989 (Box 46)
    - Medusa Frequency--notes and drafts, 1989 (Box 46)
    - Fremder--draft, 1983 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft, 1983 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft (pages 3-35), 1983 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft titled "Fremnew" (pages 1-40), 1983 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--notes and odd pages, 1983-1985 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft, 1985 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft (jumbled), 1989-1990 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft marked "Fremd4" (jumbled), 1990 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft (confusingly ordered), 1990 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft (pages 56-1), 1990 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft, 1990-1994 (Box 47)
    - Fremder--draft (unordered), 1991 (Box 48)
    - Fremder--draft (pages 119-1), 1991 (Box 48)
    - Fremder--draft (unordered pages and notes), 1991-1992 (Box 48)
    - Fremder--draft, 1993 (Box 48)
    - Fremder--draft, 1994 (Box 48)
    - Fremder--draft, 1994 (Box 48)
    - Fremder--draft, notes and songs, 1997-07 (Box 49)
    - The Trokeville Way, 1996 (Box 49)
    - The Trokeville Way--draft (pages 1-30), 1992-03-1993-04 (Box 49)
    - The Trokeville Way--alternative page 6's, 1990-09 (Box 49)
    - Mr. Ringo-Clacton's Offer, 1996-05-1997-01; (2 folders) (Box 49)
    - Mr. Ringo-Clacton's Offer, 1997-01-1997-05 (Box 49)
    - Assorted illustrations from Amaryllis Night and Day, 2000 (Box 50)
    - Amaryllis--draft (2nd half), 2000 (Box 50)
    - Amaryllis--draft (1st half), 1999-2000 (Box 50)
    - Amaryllis--drafts entitled "Glims, 1999-2000 (Box 50)
    - Angelica's Grotto--draft (Chapter 28-50), 1998-1999 (Box 50)
    - Angelica's Grotto--draft (Chapter 1-27), 1998-1999 (Box 50)
    - Angelica's Grotto--story notes, 1997 (Box 50)
    - Her Name was Lola--draft, 2002 (Box 51)
    - Her Name was Lola--draft, 2002 (Box 51)
    - Bat Tattoo--draft titled "Mayb" (Chapter 1-10), 2001 (Box 51)
    - Bat Tattoo--draft with notes (Chapter 12-32), 2001 (Box 51)
    - Bat Tattoo--draft (Chapters 1-12), 2001 (Box 51)
    - Bat Tattoo--draft (Chapters 14-28), 2001 (Box 51)
    - Bat Tattoo--draft (Chapters 15-21), 2000-2001 (Box 52)
    - Bat Tattoo--draft, 2000 (Box 52)
    - Bat Tattoo--draft (Chapters 1-14), 2000-2001 (Box 52)
    - Angelica Lost and Found--final draft, circa 2010 (Box 53)
    - Angelica Lost and Found--final draft, circa 2010 (Box 53)
    - Angelica Lost and Found, circa 2010 (Box 53)
    - Angelica Lost and Found, circa 2010 (Box 53)
    - Angelica Lost and Found, 2010 (Box 54)
    - Angelica Lost and Found, 2009-2010 (Box 54)
    - Angelica Lost and Found--draft, 2008 (Box 54)
    - Angelica Lost and Found--early opening, 2008 (Box 54)
    - Notes on Aristo and paintings, circa 1994-1995 (Box 54)
    - Almost Falling--unpublished draft, 2007 (Box 55)
    - My Tango with Barbara Strozzi, 2006 (Box 55)
    - My Tango with Barbara Strozzi, 2006 (Box 55)
    - Notes on "Tango", 1998-1999 (Box 55)
    - Linger Awhile--draft, 2003 (Box 56)
    - Come Dance with Me--draft, 2003 (Box 56)
    - Come Dance with Me, 2002 (Box 56)
    - Sometimes La Comparsa, 2010-01 (Box 57)
    - Sometimes La Comparsa--unpublished draft, 2010 May - June (Box 57)
      Contains musical score.
    - The Mirror of Prester John--unpublished draft, 2010 April (Box 57)
      Contains notes.
    - The Mirror of Prester John--unpublished draft, 2010 April - 2011 March (Box 57)
    - The Mirror of Prester John--draft, 2011 January - March (Box 57)
    - Soonchild--early draft, 1987 November (Box 57)
    - Soonchild "Owl Woman"--early draft, 1987 November (Box 57)
    - Soonchild--early draft, 1987 November - 1988 March (Box 57)
    - Soonchild--early draft, 1987 December - 1988 January (Box 58)
    - Soonchild "Owl Woman"--brochures and notes, circa 1988 (Box 58)
    - Soonchild--early drafts, 1988 February (Box 58)
    - Soonchild, chapter 3--draft, 1988 March (Box 58)
    - Soonchild--early draft, 1988 March - February (Box 58)
    - Soonchild--notes and sketches, 1988 January - 1989 July (Box 58)
    - Soonchild--drafts, 1988 January - 1989 September (Box 58)
    - Soonchild--notes and drafts, 1988 April - 1989 May (Box 58)
      Contains loose and unordered pages.
    - Soonchild--early drafts, 1989 June (Box 58)
    - Soonchild--early draft and notes, 1989 September (Box 58)
    - Soonchild--drafts and notes, 1989 September - 1990 March (Box 58)
    - Soonchild--partial first draft, 1990 November - December (Box 58)
      Contains loose pages.
    - Soonchild--draft (pages 1-69), 1991 February (Box 58)
    - Soonchild--draft (pages 1-69), 1991 February (Box 59)
    - Soonchild--draft (with apparent name change), 2009 March - August (Box 59)
    - Soonchild--final draft, 2009 November 5 (Box 59)
    - Soonchild--draft, 2009 August - 2010 May (Box 59)
      Includes letters relating to publication, as well as personal correspondence.
    - Soonchild--draft, 2009 August - 2010 May (Box 59)
      Includes letter to "Maria."
    - Soonchild--final print draft with illustrations, 2012 (Box 59)
    - Soonchild "Old Woman", undated (Box 59)
  - Unsorted notes, writings, and ephemera
    - Granta party photograph, undated (Box 60)
    - "The Listener" magazine, 1984 (Box 60)
    - The Way We Die Now, 1984 (Box 60)
    - Orpheus Nightman sketch, 1984 (Box 60)
    - The Radio Magician, 1984 (Box 60)
    - Unidentified notes and drafts, 1980 (Box 60)
    - "Second Mrs. Kong" signed cast list and photograph, 1994 (Box 60)
    - Notes on the Brothers Grimm, undated (Box 60)
    - Short pieces, undated (Box 60)
    - Collection of images and illustrations, undated (Box 60)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 60)
    - Notes on Trieres, undated (Box 60)
    - Reading list, undated (Box 60)
    - Notes on maritime history, undated (Box 60)
    - "On Teaching" pamphlet, undated (Box 60)
    - "Source" magazine with Russell Hoban feature, 2007 (Box 61)
    - Interview with James Carter, circa 1996 (Box 61)
    - Interview for "What" magazine, 1987 (Box 61)
    - Notes on Vermeer, 1995 (Box 61)
    - Notes on Native Americans and Crazy Horse, 1995 (Box 61)
    - Auschwitz clippings and notes, circa 1995 (Box 61)
    - Notes on parapsychology, circa 1994 (Box 61)
    - "Second Mrs. Kong" vocal score, 1994 (Box 61)
    - "Second Mrs. Kong" vocal score, 1993 (Box 61)
    - Article about King Kong, ca. 1994 (Box 61)
    - Photograph of Hoban at Glyndebourne, circa 1994 (Box 61)
    - Notes on Romantic-era painters, circa 1994 (Box 61)
    - Notes and pictures about the Sphinx and General Lemonnier, circa 1991 (Box 61)
    - Notes and pictures related to "Green Man", 1989 (Box 61)
    - Notes and translations of Rilke, 1988 (Box 62)
    - Material related to "Turtle Diary" film, 1984 (Box 62)
    - Unknown interview, 1986 (Box 62)
    - "Encounter" magazine with Pilgermann extract, 1983 (Box 62)
    - Illustration notes, 1979-1981 (Box 62)
    - Clippings and materials related to "The Mouse and His Child" animated film, circa 1977 (Box 62)
    - Notes and letters for talks, circa 1975-1977 (Box 62)
    - "Portknockie" notes, 1975-1980 (Box 62)
    - Notes and sketches, circa 1972 (Box 62)
    - Account of "Saying It, Being It" experiment, circa 1973 (Box 62)
    - Notes on "The Figure in the Sand", 1971 (Box 62)
    - Unsorted handwritten notes, 1971-1979 (Box 62)
    - Clippings and published essays, circa 1971 (Box 62)
    - CV, circa 1965 (Box 62)
    - Still from King Kong, undated (Box 62)
    - The Bat Tattoo--draft, 2001 (Box 63)
    - Kleinzeit--script, undated (Box 63)
    - Come Dance--final draft, 2003 (Box 63)
    - The Second Mrs. Kong, undated; 4 (Box 68)
      Conditions Governing Access
      Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Riddley Walker, undated; 2 (Box 68)
      Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of digitial files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Audiovisual materials, undated; 3; 5 (Box 69)
      Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of Audiovisual material may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - The Bat Tattoo--draft, 2001 (Box 64)
    - Hoban booklist and unsorted pages, circa 1998-2011 (Box 64)
    - The Quadruple Sphinx, 1992 (Box 64)
    - Her Name was Lola--draft, 2002 (Box 64)
    - Come Dance with Me, 2003 (Box 64)
    - The Medusa Frequency, 1986 (Box 65)
    - The Medusa Frequency, 1986 (Box 65)
    - Riddley Walker--notes, sketches, drafts, circa 1978 (Box 65)
    - The Medusa Frequency--draft, 1986 (Box 65)
    - Riddley Walker--draft, 1979 (Box 66)
    - Slides of paintings, undated (Box 67)
      Separated Materials
      Contains seventy-eight 35mm color slides in metal slide mounts.
    - Notebook, 1991 July - 1993 April (Box 70)
    - Notebook, 1990 October - 1995 July (Box 70)
    - "Heroes and Villains" piece for The Independent Magazine, 1992 August (Box 70)
    - The Fantasy World of Russell Hoban, by A. Joan Bowers in vol 8. of Children's Literature, circa 1980 (Box 70)
    - Riddley Walker and the Novels of Russell Hoban, by Dennis Butts in The Use Of 33/3, circa 1982 (Box 70)
    - Russell Hoban: Returning to the Sunlight, by Ian D Mackillop in Good Writers for Young Readers ed. Dennis Butts, undated (Box 70)
    - Miscellaneous works, 1983-1991 (Box 70)
    - Elite Software Company mailer, undated (Box 70)
      7 compact discs and 46 floppy disks removed for separate housing.
    - Paintings and letters, by Elizabeth Collins, 1979 (Box 70)
    - "Najorks Foot Motor Boat" postcard, by Gundela Ahl, 1971 September 8 (Box 70)
    - Drafts, 1972-1999 (Box 70)
    - Publications--Russell Hoban list, undated (Box 70)
    - Cat drawings, undated (Box 70)
    - The Kraken--poem, undated (Box 70)
    - Turtle Diary--correspondence, 1985 November 24 (Box 70)
    - Night Roads, circa 1998 (Box 70)
    - Out There--draft, circa 1997 (Box 71)
    - Slides of paintings, undated (Box 72)
      Contains twenty-five 35mm color slides in metal slide mounts.
    - Audiovisual materials, undated; 8; reel to reel tapes; 1; 11 (Box 73)
    - Vol. II - General Notes--journal, circa 1982-1983 (Box 75)
      Includes laid-in ephemera.
    - Journal, circa 1983-1986 (Box 75)
      Includes a Polaroid photograph in the journal's back pocket.
    - Book notes--journal, 1988-1989 (Box 75)
    - Cricket - the magazine for Children, 1975 (Box 75)
    - Ideas, Obsessions, Intertexts: A Nonlinear Approach to Russell Hoban's Fiction by Yvonne Struder, 2000 (Box 75)
    - Glyndebourne Touring Opera, 1994 (Box 75)
    - The Mouse and His Child--wind-up mouse doll, undated (Box 75)
    - Trokeyville & dupe as of 09.02.96, circa 1996 (Box 75)
      4 floppy disks removed for separate housing.
    - Fremder, undated (Box 75)
      3 floppy disks removed for separate housing.
    - Rinyo-C Poems, Songs, undated (Box 75)
    - Fremder dupe, undated (Box 75)
    - Sea Thing [Effort] Najork music, 1978 July; 1; reel to reel tapes (Box 78)
      Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of Audiovisual material may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - The Mouse and His Child, circa 1970s; 6; reel to reel tapes (Box 78)
    - Riddley Walker and Bedtime for Frances, 1991-1996; 2 (Box 78)
      Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of Audiovisual material be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Some Episodes in the History of Miranda and Caliban--musical score, circa 1992 (Box 76)
    - On Teaching Art pamphlet, undated (Box 83)
    - Pilgermann--notes, circa 1981 (Box 83)
    - Kleinzeit--script, undated (Box 83)
    - Second Mrs. Kong--draft, 1993 (Box 83)
    - Soonchild--draft; Rosie's Magic Horse--draft, 1990-2014 (Box 83)
    - Study of the Works of Russell Hoban, 1983 (Box 83)
    - Authorities Displaced in the Novels of Russell Hoban, 1995 (Box 84)
    - Second Mrs. Kong--draft, 1993 (Box 84)
    - Angelica's Grotto--draft, 1998 (Box 84)
    - Angelica's Grotto--draft, 1998 (Box 84)
    - Audiovisual materials, undated; 6; 11; 1 (Box 85)
      1 compact disc removed for separate housing.
    - Apple IIe personal computer, undated; 1 (Box 87 (Art))
      Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      The Apple IIe is contained within its original carrying case. The keyboard keys are imprinted with Arabic letters, either painted on or engraved. It's possible these modifications are related to Russell Hoban's 1983 novel Pilgermann.
- Correspondence, 1963-2003; Series II; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Material within this series maintain the original physical organization found at time of acquisition with the exception of some oversized materials.
  Contains correspondence between Russell Hoban and many other authors, composers, and creatives, along with ephemera sometimes included with the correspondence. The material documents personal and business relationships related to Russell Hoban.
  - Postcard from Quentin Blake, 2003 (Box 16)
  - Letters to the Times, 1980 (Box 16)
  - Letter to the Times about Harrison Birtwhistle, undated (Box 16)
  - Invitation to the White House, 1991 (Box 16)
  - Letter from Arvon course, 1976 (Box 16)
  - Letter protesting censorship, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Letter to Harper Row, ca. 1964-1967 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Dorothy Wood at Penguin, 1976-1977 (Box 16)
  - Letters to Anthony Whitworth-Jones re: The Second Mrs. Kong", 1995 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Anthony Whitworth-Jones and others, 1991-1992 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Christopher Wilkins, 1984 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Kaye Webb, 1975-1983 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Brian Vickes, 1983 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Ann and Anthony Waite, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Peter Stothard, 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Catherine Storr, 1969 (Box 16)
  - Letter to Elizabeth Stabler, 1971 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Michael Sporn and John Rush, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Ilona Sekaer, 1989-2001 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Sam Youd, 1969-1975 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Ilona Sekaer, 1994 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Doreen Scott, 1994 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with John Rush, 1976-1986 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Noel Rudolph, 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Helen Roe, 1990-1996 (Box 16)
  - Letter from Roderick Poole, 1992 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Harold Pinter, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Sara Lou O'Connor, 1985-1990 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Ursula Nordstrom, 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence with Ursula Nordstrom, 1963-1969 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Jane Nissen, 1989 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Murray Braham, 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Ferdinand Monjo, 1964-1971 (Box 17)
  - Letter from Robert McNeer, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Fran Manushkin, 1971-1972 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Larry McCafferty, 1985 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Tom Maschler, 1973-1983 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence to David Maichin, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Robert D. Looms, 1975-1979 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Frances Lindley, 1972 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Jonathan Lewis, 1974 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Arthur Levine and others, 1995-1996 (Box 17)
  - Letter from Kathleen Leverich, 1976 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Barbara Lalieki, 1971-1977 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence with Jacqueline Korn, 1989 (Box 17)
  - Letter from Marianne Koch, 1983 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Lucy Ingrams, 1998 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Bruce Hunter, 1978-1991 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Richard T. Hoos, 1993-1996 (Box 18)
  - Letters from Andrew Holmes, 1973 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Elizabeth Henry, 1990-1991 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Sven Hartberger, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with David Gentleman, 1970 (Box 18)
  - Letter to Ev Greenbaum, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Letters to Bob Fawcett, 1963 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Clifton Fadiman, 1971-1974 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Harold Evans, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Letter from Maura Dooley, 1985 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Michael Dirda, 1998 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Barbara A. Dicks, 1971 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Gilles de la Mare, 1997-1998 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Walt de Faria, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Michael Croucher, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Letter to Marcus Crouch, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Helen Creswell, 1970 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Elizabeth Cree, 1995 (Box 18)
  - Letter to Nicholas Clee, 2004 (Box 18)
  - Letter to Marianne Carus, 1972 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with James Carter, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Peter Carr, 1990 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Rosemary Carter, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Andrew Bown, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Ward Botsford, 1976 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Lucy M. Boston, 1969 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Quentin Baker, 1989-1997 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Joan Ashworth, 1995 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence with Gillon Aitken and Jeremy Payton, 1991-1993 (Box 18)
- Writings on Russell and Lillian Hoban, 1964-1992; Series III; 0.42; (1 box)
  Contains articles and other writings related to the lives and works of Russell Hoban and Lillian Hoban.
  - Das Muster in Bewegung, 1992 (Box 23)
  - Das Muster in Bewegung, 1992 (Box 23)
  - Interview with Yvonne Struder, 1991 (Box 23)
  - "Literature in Altered Englishes"--dissertation by Franci Celoria, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Study on Hoban's books for University of Zurich, 1989 (Box 23)
  - "Is There Hope of Anything?"--dissertation by Geneve Van Osch, 1987 (Box 23)
  - "Fiction" magazine featuring Pilgermann Review, 1983 (Box 23)
  - Hoban feature in People Weekly, 1981 (Box 23)
  - Harper and Row leaflet featuring Russell and Lillian Hoban, circa 1969 (Box 23)
  - Russell and Lillian Hoban biographies, circa 1964 (Box 23)
- Diaries, 1956-2005; Series IV; 4.33; (4 boxes)
  Contains calendar books annotated by Russell Hoban.
  - Diary, 1956 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1957 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1958 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1959 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1960 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1961 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1963 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1964 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1965 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1966 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1967 (Box 79)
  - Diary, 1968 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1969 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1970 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1971 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1972 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1973 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1975 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1976 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1977 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1978 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1979 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1980 (Box 80)
  - Diary, 1981 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1982 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1983 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1984 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1985 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1986 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1987 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1988 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1989 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1990 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1991 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1992 (Box 81)
  - Diary, 1993 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 1994 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 1995 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 1996 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 1997 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 1998 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 1999 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 2000 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 2001 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 2002 (Box 82)
  - Diary, 2005 (Box 82)
- Artwork, circa 1952-1980; Series V; 0.42; (2 boxes)
  Material within this series maintain the original organization found at time of acquisition with the exception of some oversized materials.
  Contains artwork created by Russell Hoban.
  - Assorted sketches, circa 1952-1980 (Box 60)
  - Sketch of a man, undated (Box 60)
  - "Philosophical" watercolors, undated (Box 88 (Oversize))